lazymanandmoney.com 2019-04-18

# Terms and Conditions - Lazy Man and Money

### Quick Non-Legalese Version

The stuff in the full legalese version below is standard boilerplate stuff. Some other personal finance blogger wrote it around 2007 or so and gave me permission to use it with some minor edits.

  * I have to tell you that I’m not a financial professional to protect myself legally. I could go out and get a bunch of licenses to give financial advice and I’ve thought about doing so, but then what I can write about would be legally restricted as well.
  * While I do give myself the ability to edit user comments, I’ve rarely used it… probably in less than 1 in a thousand cases. Typically it only happens when someone has a pretty good comment, but then ends with something like: “Here’s my [link to a get rich quick scheme].” I openly allow for any number of dissenting opinions (see [the comments on my MonaVie article](http://www.lazymanandmoney.com/monavie-scam/)), but in the end, I have to include this clause.
  * The advertising that I use, Google AdSense, and a number of other advertisers that I use are used by millions of sites. These advertisers require that I disclose that cookies can be used by these advertising systems. I do not get access to any of this information and can’t see any of your personal preferences, things you like, or sites you previously visited. I can get the general location of my visitors such as which country they live in, but with over 4 million visitors, chances are that every country is covered by now. You are essentially anonymous to me.
  * I will never ask for, and you should never tell me any a password of any kind.
  * If you leave a comment or subscribe to receive emails, I will never sell it. I hate spam as much as you do. In fact if you leave a comment with your email address as part of the text that another user can see, I edit your comment to take out the email address so nefarious spam bots scouring my site won’t pick up your email address.

That’s pretty much it. The overriding rule here is that I don’t collect much of your information myself and I make none of it available to others. You’ll find that the legalese below is essentially the same as millions of other websites and many personal finance blogs.

### Full Legalese Version

Lazy Man and Money is not a financial professional and no content within this website should be considered financial advice. Please consult a certified financial expert before attempting any of the ideas described in this website.

Lazy Man and Money takes no responsibility for any losses incurred while following the information presented here.

The content of this site is the copyright of Lazy Man and Money. You may cite and quote content published here under the following conditions. You must cite the source (giving credit Lazy Man and Money) and you must not republish the article in it’s entirety. Only reasonable length excerpts are allowed and it highly preferred that such excerpts include additional commentary. You must not use any automated process to pull in content from this site for republishing – especially if that republishing is on a regular basis. Any exception to the above must be granted in writing (electronic e-mail is sufficient) by Lazy Man and Money.

User-generated content (such as comments) are subject to editing by Lazy Man and Money. This editing can include, but is not limited to, changing or omitting URLs, fixing and correcting grammar and/or spelling, and even editing the name of the commenter (usually restricted to cases where a commenter includes their website’s tagline in their name). User-generated content may be deleted by Lazy Man and Money. This is usually done in, but limited to, cases where the content is deemed inappropriate or irrelevant to the topic. By creating such content you are agreeing to the above terms and conditions. Users are solely responsible and liable for their content. By generating content, the user grants license to the blog owner to use, modify, delete, sell, etc. all content. Lazy Man and Money will not revoke or modify comments at the request of the author. Policy on all user-generated content may change at any time.

**Privacy Policy:**

The privacy of our visitors to LazyManAndMoney.com is important to us. 

At Lazy Man and Money, we recognize that privacy of your personal information is important. Here is information on what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use visit Lazy Man and Money, and how we safeguard your information. We never sell your personal information to third parties.

**Log Files**  
As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.

We also use third party advertisements on Lazy Man and Money to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites). These advertisers may also use interest-based advertising which enables advertisers to reach users based on their interests (e.g. ‘sports enthusiasts’), and allows them to show ads based on a user’s previous interactions with them, such as visits to advertiser websites.

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You should consult your browser’s user guide for more information.

Please note that blocking cookies may have a negative impact on the functions of many websites, including Lazy Man and Money. Some features of this website may cease to be available to you.

**Full Disclosure**

The information found on the Lazy Man and Money is provided and intended for informational and entertainment purposes only and does not constitute financial, legal, or other advice of any kind. The information contained on this site is aimed at a general audience, and does not attempt to offer specific advice to your specific circumstances. If you are looking for professional advice, you should consult with an independent financial adviser.

As required by FTC regulations, please note that we have a financial relationship with the companies mentioned on this site. We frequently review products or services that we have been given access to for free. However, we do not accept compensation in any form in exchange for positive reviews, and the reviews found on this site represent the opinions of the author.

This site contains information about third party products and services, such as credit card offers, online banking, discount brokers, and credit score services. While we endeavor to ensure that the information presented on this site is accurate at the time of publication, any offers and rates shown on the Lazy Man and Money can and do change without notice. Visit the official site of the offer for up-to-date information.

**Interest-Based Advertising**

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site. AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies. 

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners.You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: https://adssettings.google.com. You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: http://optout.networkadvertising.org. However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained. 

**For European Economic Area Residents**

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing. If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at info@adthrive.com. If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

**Other information collected by third-parties**

We may allow third-party companies that use tracking technologies, such as cookies or pixels, to record IP information about users who visit or interact with our website. Our website does not provide any personal information to these third parties. This information allows them to deliver targeted advertisements and gauge their effectiveness. Some of these third-party advertising companies may be advertising networks that are members of the Network Advertising Initiative which offers a single location to opt out of ad targeting from member companies.

**Email Addresses**

We may collect your email address, but only if you voluntarily provide it to us. This may occur, for example, if you sign up to receive an email newsletter, or enter a promotion. We will use your email address for the purposes for which you provided it to us, and also from time to time to send you emails regarding the Site or other products or services that we believe may be of interest to you. You may opt out of such email communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” button in the email.

Your email address may also be shared with the technology provider we use in connection with the purposes for which you provided it, and that technology provider may also contact you from time to time.

If you are a resident of a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), please refer to the section below entitled “Additional Rights of EEA Residents.

**Additional Rights of EEA (European Economic Area) Residents**

If you are a resident of a country in the EEA, you have the rights, among others, to:

(i) access your personal data

(ii) ensure the accuracy of your personal data

(iii) the right to have us delete your personal data

(iv) the right to restrict further processing of your personal data, and

(v) the right to complain to a supervisory authority in your country of residence in the event that data is misused

If you believe that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us addressed to the following: 

Lazy Man and Money  
P.O. Box 4814  
Middletown, RI 02842

Sale of Business or Assets

In the event that the Site or substantially all of its assets is sold or disposed of as a going concern, whether by merger, sale of assets or otherwise, or in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership, the information we have collected about you may be one of the assets sold or merged in connection with that transaction.

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most recent version of the Privacy Policy will always be posted on the Site. We may revise and update this Privacy Policy if our practices change, as technology changes, or as we add new services or change existing ones. If we make any material changes to our Privacy Policy or how we handle your personal information, or we are going to use any personal information in a manner that is materially different from that stated in our Privacy Policy at the time we collected such information, we will give you a reasonable opportunity to consent to the change. If you do not consent, your personal information will be used as agreed to under the terms of the privacy policy in effect at the time we obtained that information. By using our Site or services after the Effective Date, you are deemed to consent to our then-current privacy policy. We will use information previously obtained in accordance with the Privacy Policy in effect when the information was obtained from you.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or the practices of this Site, please contact us at lazymanandmoney@gmail.com

Or write to us at:

Lazy Man and Money  
P.O. Box 4814  
Middletown, RI 02842
